A while ago
前一阵子
A poster went around Reddit
Reddit上一张海报
And got a bit of attention
一时走红
I was surprised that
让我意外的是
A friend of mine instantly recognized it as Chinese
我的朋友凭着画幅上的留白
With the use of white, negative space
一眼看出这是中国的海报
It's only then, I realized that
我才意识到
Different countries approach posters very differently
不同国家对海报的设计概念大不相同
I never realized that
我如此迟钝
Because good posters are often underappreciated
是因为，优秀的海报往往被忽视
We don't tend to notice the good ones
很少有人评论海报设计
It's usually the bad ones that catch our eye
通常只有烂海报才会吸引我们注意力
So today, let me purge my ignorance
今天，请让我摆脱过去的无知
And explore the world of Asian movie posters
和大家一起探索东亚电影海报设计
Posters from China, Japan, and South Korea
看看来自中国，日本和韩国的海报
Let's see what each country's general design trend is
品味每个国家的总体设计趋势
And highlight a few posters that I personally love
并展示一些我个人喜欢的海报作品
Keep in mind that I'm not a graphic designer
当然了，我不是平面设计师
I only made a few posters for my own films
我只为自己的微电影制作了几张海报
So take my opinions with a grain of salt
还请大家不要对我的意见太较真
I'll stick to mostly recent films
我会集中选择近期作品
Since there really isn't much to talk about
毕竟“ Photoshop”时代的臭烂作品
With regards to the infamous "Photoshop" age
真是没什么好评论的
Everyone suffered back then
那段时间，大家都在受苦
Like, why is this guy transparent...?
你说，陈道明为什么要半透明？
So, let's give them the admiration
那么，让我们好好欣赏
They rightly deserve
这些常被忽略的艺术品吧
If you look up Chinese posters on Google
在网上查找中国海报
You'd find a lot of cases of plagiarism
恐怕会马上找到各种抄袭案例
Unlike Japan and Korea
与日本和韩国不同
The Chinese film market really only became big
中国电影市场只有近几年
In the past decade or so
才开始真正入主流
The market has yet to value posters as an art form
市场尚未将海报视为艺术
As with any starting player
作为游戏里的新玩家
With no budget
没有预算
And even less time
没有时间
The best an overworked, underpaid graphic designer can muster
工作过度又薪水不足的设计师们
Is to copy someone
没有发挥创意的空间
Who best to copy
新玩家要抄袭
Than the biggest player in the world, Hollywood?
那当然要抄好莱坞
The only problem
然而
Is that Hollywood blockbuster posters in general suck pretty hard
好莱坞的大片海报其实也十分烂渣
They are notoriously unimaginative
出了名的缺乏创意
As a result
结果就是
Many Chinese posters end up feeling
许多中国海报给人感觉
Both cheap and uninspired
既便宜又山寨
Wandering Earth's main poster is atrocious
《流浪地球》的人物海报烂爆了
I hate posters where characters just stand there
我最讨厌就是人物站直
Doing nothing
无所事事的海报
It's just an illustrated list of actors
说半天，就是一张演员清单
And a badly photoshopped one at that
这还P得特别不像话
But its scenic posters are pretty amazing
但是《流浪地球》的风景海报则优秀很多
After all, the actors in the film aren’t the draw
说到底，电影中的演员不是亮点
It is the world-building
亮点是世界观
But my favorite is this one
但我最喜欢的海报还是这张
In which it captures the main selling point of the film
它抓住了电影的主要卖点
Being an adaptation of the Chinese Sci-Fi classic
清楚告诉大家，这是中国科幻小说的电影版
Look at those old and worn out pages
破旧的页面
Stabled together
被订在一起
Capturing that post-apocalyptic feel of the film
表达出了电影里的末日感
Where society is barely functional
人类社会勉强运转的风格
But my favorite is how it illustrates the story
我还特别喜欢的是它表达剧情的方式
The story of Earth leaving the solar system behind
电影里，人类带着地球离开太阳系
On this image, every planet is listed
海报列出了太阳系地球以外
Except for Earth
每个行星
Intriguingly missing, leaving an empty spot
地球原处，留下空白
That's a sick concept if you ask me
如此精妙，让人拍案叫绝
Much like this poster
和《流浪地球》一样
When Chinese posters get good
中国海报优秀起来
They get REALLY good
基本没别人什么事
Most of the best Chinese posters out there
中国海报里最优秀的作品
Are all design by one man and his company
一大部分都是由一个人和他公司所制作的
Huang Hai
这个人就是黄海
Their posters are beautifully poetic
他们的海报极富诗意
And very visually striking
构图十分出彩
The Golden Era tells the story of a woman activist and novelist
《黄金时代》讲述生活在战时中国
Living in wartime China
一位小说家的故事
The tilt-shift effect and the high angle shot
高角度俯视
Looks down onto her, as if she's a miniature model
她看起来如此渺小
The seemingly random splashes of ink
看着凌乱的墨水
Paints the big world she's living in
描绘她所生活的大世界
Signifying the chaotic time the film is set in
象征着战争时期的中国
And signifies how much influence her, as a writer
都代表着作家文字对世界
Has on the world
所持有的影响力
Oh, and the international poster is also really good
该片的国际海报也十分优秀
My favorite Huang Hai poster has to be Masters in Forbidden City
我最喜欢的黄海海报是《我在故宫修文物》
It's a film about museum workers
这是一部关于博物馆工作人员
Repairing and restoring historical relics
修复历史文物的纪录片
The poster relies almost solely on the beauty of these artifacts
海报朴素地展示这些文物自身的美丽
What makes this poster special
当让这张海报脱颖而出的地方
Is here
在这里
This is what Chinese people describe as
这就是中国人所说的
"Drawing the eye of the dragon"
画龙点睛
Giving life to an art piece
让艺术品活过来的亮点
The shape of this worker is tiny
工人形体之小
Insignificant
微不足道
While the relic is immense
而文物如此庞大
It captures the feeling of restoration perfectly
表现出了修复文物的艰巨
It is a delicate and tedious task
过程如此繁复
It takes sometimes years just to repair one relic
有时需要数年才能修复一件作品
Yet it also captures that feeling of history
同时，它又捕捉到了历史感
A moment in time
在历史长河里的瞬间
As the tagline suggests
正如标语所示
Big history, Small craftsmen
大历史，小工匠
Of course, Huang Hai isn't the only one who makes good posters
当然，黄海并不是独占中国海报市场
Brotherhood of Blades 2 is visually beautiful
《绣春刀2》的构图十分美丽
But what's interesting is how small the actress is
然而亮点是，海报上的女角色如此渺小
Yang Mi is a very high profile star in Mainland China
杨幂是中国大陆知名度很高的明星
And is absolutely someone to draw in more box office revenue
绝对是增加票房的卖点之一
The decision to leave her so tiny is bold, to say the least
把她弄的那么小，可谓十分大胆
But it works
不过，也说得通
The beautiful composition draws you in
海报的构图先吸引住人
The empty space leaving you wanting for more
大幅度的留白让你进一步细看
So you read the text
看哪里呢？看文字
That's how you find out who she is
这样你就知道她是谁了
And once you went through this process
东西都看过一遍了
You are not forgetting this poster ever again
你一时半会，也是忘不了这张海报了
Many Chinese animations also have great posters
中国动画的海报似乎也比较优秀
I'm guessing it's because the studio already knows how to draw
大概是因为工作室本身就会画画
Big Fish and Begonia's poster is just...
《大鱼海棠》的海报可谓...
Wow
哇哦
But its quaint character posters are also really beautiful
但是它的角色海报也十分好看
Makes me wish the entire film looks like this instead
真希望整部电影都是这个画风
White Snake has a spectacular hand-drawn poster
《白蛇：缘起》的手绘海报甚是壮观
Even if it doesn't really reflect the film's art style
尽管画风与电影本身差距甚广
Its international poster however
电影的国际海报
Is next level
则更上一层楼
White Snake is a story about seeing humanities in monsters
《白蛇传》的故事里，妖怪亦有人性
The eye of a snake monster seeing its past memories
蛇精的眼里，看到过去的回忆
And tearing up
流出眼泪
Is the perfect visual summary
一张图，表达出了《白蛇》的精髓
In recent years
近几年里
Great posters became a hot topic in China
能经常看到优秀海报在中国社交网络上走红
More and more people are paying attention to this art form
越来越多的人开始关注这种艺术形式
If these beautiful posters for Ghibli movie re-release are any indication
根据这些中国设计的吉卜力海报来看
The Chinese poster industry
中国海报行业的前景
Is going to be something very special
将是十分亮丽
Now let's travel to Japan
下一站，日本
In terms of general design trend
就趋势而言
Japanese live-action films love this manga panel design
日本电影喜欢这种漫画面板设计
It's hard to make screengrabs look good in posters
截屏海报一般都不是很好看
As it tends to look flat, busy, and out of place
视觉上既平坦，又忙乱
But Japanese poster designs mastered it
但是日本的海报却能让截屏十分顺眼
And it is very recognizably Japanese
而且一看知道是日本电影
You rarely see other countries do this
很少有其他国家这样设计海报的
More often than not, I find it to be very pleasing
大多数情况下，我都觉得这种构图挺好看的
Even if it's very overused
虽然也是有点烂大街
Still, Japan is not immune to Mount Rushmore posters
当然了，日本也不是没有大头海报
At its best, you have this
好看的大头，大概如此
Which is aesthetically pleasing
构图好看
But otherwise lacking in metaphor
但缺乏隐喻
At least I don't see it
反正我是看不出隐喻啦
At worse, you have this
糟糕一点，则有这种
I don't know why
不知道为什么
Anime and manga adaptations tend to come with
动漫改编作品的海报
The worse posters
往往特别差劲
This is worse than Wandering Earth
这比《流浪地球》还糟
It does have one exception:
不过，这也有例外
The poster for Death Note focuses on the two main characters
《死亡笔记》的海报着重于两个主角
Or rather, the pitch-perfect recreation of them
更确切地说，是展示了两位主角的还原度
As if reassuring the audience
似乎是让观众知道
That this is more than a cosplay
这部电影，不仅仅是cosplay
But the one I like is the one featuring Light
但我喜欢的是夜神月的个人海报
Backlit
背光
Dark clothes on dark background
深色背景，配深色衣服
It's sinister
邪恶感满满
But the real highlight is the apple
真正的亮点在于苹果
The symbol of sin
原罪的象征
Is it floating?
这是浮起来
Or is it falling?
还是在往下掉？
Or is it holding up by an invisible being
亦还是被一个隐形的生物拿着？
In this composition
这个构图里
Your eyes jump between Light's face
你的眼睛在夜神月的脸
His hand
手
And the apple
和苹果之间来回
The ambiguity is intriguing
让人模凌两可的感觉
But also symbolizes Light as a character
表达着光的正义和邪恶感
Perfectly
完美重现
Still, my favorite live-action Japanese poster
不过，我最喜欢的真人电影海报
Has to be this one
还是这张
Instead of going for movements like most posters
大多数海报偏爱展示动态画面
This film goes for stillness
这张海报则偏好静态
With the two birds resting on the hilt of a sword
两只鸟停留剑柄上
It feels both calming
感觉既平和
And foreboding
又不祥
Makes even more sense when you realize
如此海报来表达一位盲人剑客的故事
The film features a blind swordsman
可谓贴切不过
But really
不过啊
When it comes to Japanese cinema
说到日本电影
Animated movies are the current king
动画电影才是重点
Your Name's poster is all-around well done
《你的名字》海报做得很好
Low Angle to show off the beautiful sky
低角度，展示美丽的天空
Something that Makoto Shinkai is known for
新海诚的标志构图
Image splits in half while remaining connected
图片分成两半，但又保持连接
Reflecting on the film's parallel storylines
反映出电影的两条故事线
What I'm always amazed by, however
然而最让我佩服的
Is the text layout
是文字排版
Japanese posters almost always have this uncanny ability
日本海报总有种不可思议的能力
To make a wall of text look clean
能让一堆文字看起来清爽无比
Here's the English version for comparison
英文版海报就做不到
The poster for The Journalist took it to the extreme
《新闻记者》的海报将文字排版推向极致
As the title suggests
正如电影名字
It's a film about investigative journalism
这是一部关于调查新闻的电影
It cleverly uses the text in the format of a newspaper
它巧妙地使用报纸格式
To tell you the title
列出了标题
The hook
剧情
The list of actors
演员名单
And the time it'll be in theatres
以及上映时间
All while using the gaps to highlight the two characters
同时还利用文字之间的空白，衬托出了两位角色
Of course, there are also split panels down the bottom
当然，底部还有一些板块
It is a Japanese film after all
毕竟是日本电影嘛
Back to Anime
回到动画
Hello World is a film about preserving old culture
《Hello World》的故事里，人类正利用科技
Through the use of technology
来保存传统文化和建筑
The upper, technology-themed part of the image
图像的上部，充满科技感
Is mirrored in the bottom half with nature and older architecture
下部，以旧建筑做出倒影
Representing the struggle between the two
象征着两个主题的冲撞
At the bottom, two characters hold hands
最下方，两个角色牵着手
Showing the true message of the film
展现电影的主题
That the connection of human heart is the key
人心的联系才是关键
The poster for A Silent Voice doesn't seem very special
《声之形》的海报看似简单
Outside of its fantastic art style
画风也是清新可爱
But it does have one neat thing
但海报还是有个小亮点的
And it's pretty obvious when you see it
而且其实十分明显
Shoko, the girl here
硝子，这个的女孩
Is the only one who's not facing left
是唯一一个没有面向左方的人
She's almost, but not quite looking at the camera
她几乎，但又没有看着镜头
In fact, she's looking at nothing
事实上，她的双眼正放空
She's in her little own world
她活在了自己的小世界里
In the film, Shoko is deaf
电影中，硝子是个听障少女
And this poster, through one image
而这张海报，通过一张图片
Captures her emotional isolation from other people
表现出了她与其他人的间隙
And then, there is Tokyo Godfathers
《东京教父》的海报里
Characters stacking on top of chaotically arranged skyscrapers
三位角色爬在了凌乱堆叠其的摩天大楼上
Representing their frantic journey through  Tokyo
象征着他们穿越东京的疯狂旅程
But did you notice that everything is arranged
然而，你有没有注意到，这整张图
In the shape of a Christmas tree
其实是一棵圣诞树？
Finally, there is Paprika
《盗梦侦探》的故事里
A film about dreams
角色可以进入他人梦境
And just like its premise
跟这个剧情设定一样
The poster is visually crazy
海报视觉设计也是十分疯狂
If not a bit seductive
而且还有点性感
The poster overlays this madness of dreams
梦的疯狂元素覆盖着整张海报
Onto the body of the main character
印在主角身上
In the style similar to traditional Japanese tattoo
风格酷似日本传统刺青
Like every dream has an effect on your body
仿佛象征着梦对人的影响
Imprinting itself onto your identity
烙印在每个人的身上
I, however, prefer the DVD cover
我个人更喜欢电影的DVD封面
The close up of the face covered in madness
脸的特写，盖满了梦境画面
With the eyes standing out
双眼看着镜头
Highlighted by the shape of the hair
头发形状烘托双眼
You can't help but stare at it
让人忍不住凝视
When your eyes meet
盯着双眼看久了
It draws you in
会被吸引住
And now
然后
You are in her mind
你就进入到了
In her dreams
她的梦里
Mesmerizing
真迷人
I know I said I don't like Mount Rushmore posters
我说了，我不喜欢大头海报
But man, the South Korean film industry sure makes it work
但是韩国电影业却很喜欢这种海报
Faces are the main trend of recent Korean movie posters
人脸是韩国电影海报的主要风格
But it's not just faces on posters
但这些海报都不止是人脸
There's always something interesting going on
设计上，一般都有一些小亮点
And you can usually guess the theme or plot of the movie
而通过这些亮点，观众一般能猜到剧情或主题
Oldboy has this uneven close up versus medium split
《老男孩》以一半中景，一半特别为构图
They feel conflicting, contrasting
左右两边有着强烈冲击感
Yet because of the size differences
但是由于尺寸差异
They feel distant
两者有感觉十分遥远
Like they are plotting something against each other
似乎在互相图谋
What a way to show conflicts
这样表达冲突，绝妙
Forgotten is the total opposite
《记忆之夜》则完全相反
It nearly perfectly matches the two faces
几乎完美地将两张脸融为一体
Making it uncomfortable to look at
直视时有种不安感
Just like the poster
和海报一样
The movie is a total mindf*ck
这部电影十分烧脑
Dealing with multiple identities of multiple people
剧情关乎多个人的多重身份
All entangled into one unifying conspiracy
交叉连接一起的巨大谜团
Monster took a familiar big head poster concept
《怪物》采用了熟悉的大头贴海报概念
And throws a twist into it
并添加了额外的元素
The two heads along with the striking arm and claw
两个人头，加上一只手臂
Creates a triangle for your eyes to wander back and forth
形成一个三角形，让眼睛来回漫游
With a title like this
这个标题
It just makes you wonder
让人不禁问
WHO is the monster?
谁才是怪物？
The girl who's holding him by the neck?
掐住他脖子的女孩？
Or the man who's smirking while all this is happening?
还是若无其事在冷笑的男孩？
Now that's not saying there aren't generic big head posters
当然，韩国的大头海报也不是每一张都出彩
But even when they are generic
但即使不出彩
There's usually a strong composition
一般构图感都会十分强
To prevent it from being bad
很少有真正的烂作
Some times, movies would take the big head concept
有时候，电影会用大头的设计感
And use it on medium or wide shots
运用在中景或广角构图上
People just stand there
海报上的人就站在那里
Graduation photo style
拍毕业照似的
And just like their big head counterpart
而跟大头海报一样
The good ones always have a twist
优秀的作品，往往另有亮点
One of the most memorable ones
最让人难忘的
Is A Tale of Two Sisters
我想是《鬼魅》
What a poster
惊艳
The image splits into two parts
海报分为两部分
With the parents dressed in black on top
上部，父母黑色正装
Mirrored by the two sisters dressed in white
下部，两姐妹身穿白色裙
The immediate interest is the blood all over the two
红色的鲜血冲击力极强
But did you noticed the two sisters
但你有没有注意到
Are in very similar gestures to their parents?
两姐妹的姿势其实与父母一致？
One with her back straight
一边，两人挺直了背
The other with one hand to the side?
另一边，右手向外
But instead of confident and assertive
但与父母的自信不同
The sisters look weak and lifeless
姐妹们看起来虚弱无力
As if they are puppets of their parents
仿佛是父母的傀儡
Of course, who can forget about Parasite
当然，不得不提《寄生虫》
Which has this poster
电影有这张海报
The feet at the bottom
左下角的脚
Is, of course, the biggest interest point
当然是海报亮点
It also puts the entire image off balance
打破了构图的平衡
Giving it a twisted feel that matches with the film itself
给人一种扭曲感，与电影本身气氛酷似
But the group itself is also intriguing
但是上方八人本身也很有趣
It contains two families
海报里有两个家庭
One rich, one poor
一富一穷
How can you tell?
怎么看出来的呢？
Well, the poor family members aren't wearing shoes
因为穷人们都没有穿鞋
Overall, Korean posters appear to be the most consistent
总体而言，韩国海报应该是三个国家之间
Among the three countries, we discussed today
水准最稳定的
Although at times
尽管有时
It does get pretty samey
真是稳定的有点乏味
But rarely is a poster downright bad
但很少有海报是彻头彻尾的烂
That speaks to the overall robustness
可见韩国电影业的
Of South Korean cinema
整体壮大和健全
Respect
致敬
If there's ever a picture that worths a thousand words
要说“一画胜千言”
That picture would've been a poster
那幅画，多半是张海报
Condensing an entire script
把整个剧本概括起来
Distilling an entire movie
把整部电影容纳在
Down to one single frame
一幅画里
That is an art
那是一门艺术
I took the liberty to redesign the poster for Pure Hearts
把《纯洁心灵》的海报改成这样
See how it changes your expectation
对电影整体的观感和期待
And the perception of the film?
马上就变了
I bet at this moment
我敢打赌
Every single one of you still remembers most posters
此时此刻，你们每个人都还记得视频里
Shown in this video
展示过的大部分海报
And many of you became curious about the movies
相信有不少人仅仅因为这些海报
Simply because of the posters I showed
就对其中几部电影有了兴趣
That's the power of a good poster
这就是优秀海报的吸引力
Next time
下次
When you walk past one
当你经过一张海报
Give it a closer look
仔细看看
On that image
海报上的细节
Are details, crafted by artists
都是艺术家的心血